{"name": "ST1  1996", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. On a math test, 12 students earned an A. This number is exactly 25% of the total number of students in the class. How many students are in the class?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "16", "C": "21", "D": "30", "E": "48"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. In the figure below, points A, E, and D are on the same line. What is the measure of \u2220CED \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "80\u00b0", "B": "90\u00b0", "C": "100\u00b0", "D": "110\u00b0", "E": "140\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. What is the fifth term of the arithmetic sequence 8, 6, 4, \u00b7\u00b7\u00b7 \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "0", "C": "4", "D": "8", "E": "16"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What value of x solves the following proportion?                     ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "11", "E": "12"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. If point C bisects line segment AB, then which of the following congruences must hold?", "choices": {"A": "CA \u224c AB ", "B": "CB \u224c AB", "C": "AC \u224c BA", "D": "BC \u224c BA ", "E": "AC \u224c CB "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Three pieces of wire, each 2.8 meters long, are cut from the end of a wire 90 meters long. How many meters of wire are left?", "choices": {"A": "81.6", "B": "82.6", "C": "83.2", "D": "83.6", "E": "87.2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. If x = -3, then 12 - 2(x + 1) = ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "7", "C": "16", "D": "19", "E": "20"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. -|-10| - (-10) = ?", "choices": {"A": "-100", "B": "-20", "C": "0", "D": "20", "E": "100"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Umberto's mother expects an increase of 5% in her current annual salary of $36,000. What would her new annual salary be?", "choices": {"A": "$36,005 ", "B": "$36,180 ", "C": "$37,800 ", "D": "$41,000 ", "E": "$54,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. If x3 =20 (and x is a real number), then x lies between which two consecutive integers?", "choices": {"A": "2 and 3", "B": "3 and 4 ", "C": "4 and 5", "D": "5 and 6", "E": "6 and 7"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. If 78 - x = 234, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-312", "B": "-156", "C": "3", "D": "156", "E": "312"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In a laboratory experiment, Amoeba A lives 5 hours longer than Amoeba B, and Amoeba B lives twice as long as Amoeba C. If n is the lifespan of Amoeba C in hours, what is the lifespan of Amoeba A, in terms of n?", "choices": {"A": "5 + 2n ", "B": "7 + n ", "C": "7n", "D": "10n", "E": "2(5 + n)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, 3 corners of a rectangle are (1,-1), (-4,-1), and (1,-4). Where is the rectangle's fourth corner? ", "choices": {"A": "(1,4)", "B": "(-1,4)", "C": "(-1,1)", "D": "(-1,-4)", "E": "(-4,-4)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Which of the following is a simplified form of 3x - 3y + 2x?", "choices": {"A": "3(x - y + 2) ", "B": "(x - y)(3 + 2x)", "C": "x(5 - 3y) ", "D": "x - 3y ", "E": "5x - 3y"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In the parallelogram below, what is the measure of \u2220DAC ?", "choices": {"A": "20\u00b0", "B": "30\u00b0", "C": "40\u00b0", "D": "50\u00b0", "E": "70\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What is the slope of any line parallel to the line 3x + 5y = 8?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": "8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. If x &gt; 0 and 2x2 - 5x - 12 = 0, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "12"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The lengths of the sides of a triangle are 3, 8, and 9 inches. How many inches long is the shortest side of a similar triangle that has a perimeter of 60 inches?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "11", "C": "20", "D": "24", "E": "27"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Jeans that normally sell for $35.95 are on sale for 25% off. How much do they cost during the sale, to the nearest dollar?", "choices": {"A": "$9 ", "B": "$11", "C": "$26", "D": "$27", "E": "$29"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. Which of the following is a factored form of 4x3y + 4xy3?", "choices": {"A": "4x3y3(y + x)", "B": "4xy(x2 + y2)", "C": "8xy(x2 + y2)", "D": "4x3y3", "E": "8x4y4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. If 2x - y = 6, and x + 4y = 12, what is the value of y?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "0", "C": "1", "D": "2", "E": "3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. There are 16 ounces in a pound. If 1.5 pounds of hamburger costs $2.88, what is the cost per ounce?", "choices": {"A": "$0.12 ", "B": "$0.18 ", "C": "$0.88 ", "D": "$1.92 ", "E": "$4.32"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. The 2 squares in the figure below have the same dimensions. The vertex of one square is at the center of the other square. What is the area of the shaded region, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "16", "D": "32", "E": "64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. A salesperson earns (6h + 0.05t) dollars, where h is the number of hours worked, and t is the total amount of her sales. What does she earn for working 10 hours with $230.80 in sales?", "choices": {"A": "$71.54 ", "B": "$74.54 ", "C": "$175.40 ", "D": "$251.80 ", "E": "$295.80"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. A floor has the dimensions shown below. How many square feet of carpeting are needed to cover the entire floor?(Note:All angles are right angles.)", "choices": {"A": "57", "B": "72", "C": "162", "D": "270", "E": "324"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Which of the following is the graph of the solution set of x - 1 &lt; -2 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Which of the following is less than ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. What is the area, in square meters, of a right triangle with sides of length 8 meters,15 meters, and 17 meters?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "60", "C": "68", "D": "120", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. When the marching band is arranged in rows of 4 people each, the last row is one person short. When it is arranged in rows of 5, the last row is still one person short. When arranged in rows of 6, the last row is still one person short. What is the least possible number of people in the marching band?", "choices": {"A": "11", "B": "14", "C": "59", "D": "89", "E": "119"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. A triangle has sides of length 2.5 feet and 4 feet. Which of the following CANNOT be the length of the third side, in feet?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. For all a \uff1e 0\uff0c  = \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. In the right triangle below, how long is side AB ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "292 - 192", "D": "292 + 192", "E": "29 - 19"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. If the length of a square is increased by 1 inch and the width is increased by 2 inches, a rectangle is formed. If each side of the original square is x inches long, what is the area of the new rectangle, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "2x + 3", "B": "4x + 6", "C": "x2 + 2", "D": "x2 + 3x + 2", "E": "x2 + 3x + 3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. If sin \u03b1 = , and cos \u03b1 = , then tan \u03b1 = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Which of the following best describes the graph on the number line below?", "choices": {"A": "|x| = -1 ", "B": "|x| &lt; 0.5 ", "C": "-2 &lt; x &lt; 0 ", "D": "-0.5 &lt; x &lt; -1.5 ", "E": "-0.5 &gt; x &gt; -1.5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. A performance was rated on a 3-point scale by an audience. A rating of 1 was given by 30% of the audience, a rating of 2 by 60%, and a rating of 3 by 10%. To the nearest tenth, what was the average of the ratings?", "choices": {"A": "1.2", "B": "1.5", "C": "1.8", "D": "2.0", "E": "2.2"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. In the right triangle below, if BC is 4 inches long, how many inches long is AB ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. What is the largest possible product for 2 even integers whose sum is 38 ?", "choices": {"A": "72", "B": "76", "C": "136", "D": "280", "E": "360"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In the figure below, lines j and k are parallel, lines m and n are parallel, and the measures of 2 angles are shown. What is the measure of \u2220x?", "choices": {"A": "45\u00b0", "B": "55\u00b0", "C": "65\u00b0", "D": "75\u00b0", "E": "80\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In the (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the y-intercept of the line 6x - 2y = 6?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "-2", "C": "0", "D": "3", "E": "6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Among the points graphed on the number line below, which is closest to \u03c0 ?(Note: \u03c0 \u2248 3.1415926) ", "choices": {"A": "A", "B": "B", "C": "C", "D": "D", "E": "E"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. For what value of a would the following system of equations have an infinite number of solutions?     2x -   y = 6      8x - 4y = 3a ", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "8", "D": "18", "E": "24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The expression (180 - x) is the degree measure of a nonzero acute angle if and only if:", "choices": {"A": "0 &lt; x &lt; 45 ", "B": "0 &lt; x &lt; 90 ", "C": "45 &lt; x &lt; 90 ", "D": "90 &lt; x &lt; 135 ", "E": "90 &lt; x &lt; 180"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. If x + y = -2, and x - y = -3, then x2 - y2= ?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "6", "C": "5", "D": "-5", "E": "-6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The sides of a triangle are 5, 12, and 13 inches long. What is the angle between the 2 shortest sides?", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "45\u00b0", "C": "60\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0", "E": "120\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, if the x-coordinate of each point on a line is 4 less than twice its y-coordinate, the slope of the line is:", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "-2", "C": "", "D": "2", "E": "4"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. From a hot air balloon, the angle between a radio antenna straight below and the base of the library downtown is 57\u00b0, as shown below.If the distance between the radio antenna and the library is 1.3 miles, how many miles high is the balloon?", "choices": {"A": "1.3 sin 57\u00b0", "B": "1.3 tan 57\u00b0", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Two numbers have a greatest common factor of 4 and a least common multiple of 24. Which of the following could be the pair of numbers?", "choices": {"A": "4 and 8 ", "B": "4 and 12 ", "C": "8 and 12 ", "D": "8 and 24 ", "E": "12 and 24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Listed below are 5 functions, each denoted g(x) and each involving a real number constant c \u2265 2.If f(x) = 2x, which of these 5 functions yields the greatest value for f(g(x)),for all x &gt; 1?", "choices": {"A": "g(x) = cx ", "B": "g(x) = ", "C": "g(x) = ", "D": "g(x) = x - c", "E": "g(x) = logc x"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Line segments AB, BC, and CD, which represent the 3 dimensions of the rectangular box shown below, have lengths of 4 inches, 3 inches, and 5 inches, respectively. What is the sine of \u2220DAC?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. A certain circle has an area of \u03c0 square inches. How many inches long is its radius?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": "\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The equation of line s below is y = mx + b. Which of the following could be an equation for line t?", "choices": {"A": "y = 2mx ", "B": "y = 2mx + b ", "C": "y = 2mx - b ", "D": "y =-2mx + b ", "E": "y =-2mx - b"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The equation x2 - 10x + k = 0 has only one solution for x. What is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "5", "C": "10", "D": "20", "E": "25"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line that passes through the origin and the point (,) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. If A, B, and C are real numbers, and if ABC = 1, which of the following conditions must be true?", "choices": {"A": "AB is equal to ", "B": "A, B, and C must all be positive ", "C": "Either A = 1, B = 1, or C = 1 ", "D": "Either A = 0, B = 0, or C = 0", "E": "Either A \uff1c 1, B \uff1c 1, or C \uff1c 1 "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The length of a rectangle is (x + 5) units and its width is (x + 7) units. Which of the following expresses the remaining area of the rectangle, in square units, if a square, x units in length, is removed from the interior of the rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "35", "C": "2x + 12", "D": "12x + 35", "E": "x2 + 12x +35"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. What is the smallest positive value for x where y = sin 2x reaches its maximum?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " \u03c0", "C": "", "D": "2\u03c0", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. In the standard(x,y) coordinate plane, if the distance between points (8,a) and (a,1) is 5 coordinate units, which of the following could be the value of a?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "3", "C": "-3", "D": "-4", "E": "-5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Martin has an empty bag and puts in 3 red marbles. He now wants to put in enough green marbles so the probability of drawing a red marble at random from the bag is . How many green marbles should he put in?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "9", "E": "12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. How many different integer values of n satisfy the inequality \uff1c  \uff1c  \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "E"}]}